=Stitching Life and Death=
=خياطة الحياة والموت=
=Episode 17=
=الحلقة 17=
Mercy, my good sir! Have mercy!
ارحم، يا سيدي الطيب! ارحم!
Open your eyes.
افتح عينيك.
I know how it goes. I'll be silenced as soon as I see your faces.
أعرف كيف تسير الأمور. سيتم إسكاتي بمجرد أن أرى وجوهكم.
I'm not seeing anything!
لا أرى شيئًا!
Was I not clear?
هل كنت غير واضح؟
Sir.
سيدي.
That's a bit much.
هذا كثير بعض الشيء.
Please open your eyes.
من فضلك افتح عينيك.
We brought you here
أحضرناك إلى هنا
just to have you testify.
فقط لتشهد.
Gladly.
بكل سرور.
Good man.
رجل طيب.
(Zhao's Mansion)
(قصر تشاو)
It hurts!
إنه يؤلم!
Father!
أبي!
Get Ma San here now!
أحضر ما سان إلى هنا الآن!
This is the place.
هذا هو المكان.
Open the door!
افتح الباب!
Open up!
افتح!
This is the guy.
هذا هو الرجل.
Over there!
هناك!
Master Song!
السيد سونغ!
It's me, Master Song!
إنه أنا، السيد سونغ!
I know.
أعرف.
Why are you here again?
لماذا أنت هنا مرة أخرى؟
It's me!
إنه أنا!
You know Master Song?
هل تعرف السيد سونغ؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
Master Song! Please...
السيد سونغ! من فضلك...
- Don't come in! - Let us in!
- لا تدخل! - دعنا ندخل!
Master Song!
السيد سونغ!
Stay away!
ابتعد!
You didn't kill me last time,
لم تقتلني في المرة الماضية،
and now you've brought help!
والآن جلبت المساعدة!
- What warranted this reaction? - You!
- ما الذي استدعى هذا الرد؟ - أنت!
Master Song!
السيد سونغ!
Stay away from me!
ابتعد عني!
Help!
النجدة!
Master Song!
السيد سونغ!
Master, have you ever had that feeling
سيدي، هل شعرت يومًا بذلك الشعور
where you know you forgot something,
عندما تعلم أنك نسيت شيئًا ما،
but you just can't figure out exactly what it is?
لكن لا يمكنك تحديد ما هو بالضبط؟
What exactly did you forget?
ما الذي نسيته بالضبط؟
It's like...
إنه مثل...
Did you instruct me to do something?
هل طلبت مني أن أفعل شيئًا؟
- Stop chasing me! - Stop running!
- توقف عن ملاحقتي! - توقف عن الركض!
- You stop running first.
- توقف عن الركض أولاً.
Do you need my help?
هل تحتاج إلى مساعدتي؟
Shoot!
أطلق!
Master.
سيدي.
I forgot you asked me to go
نسيت أنك طلبت مني الذهاب
to Master Song's residence.
إلى مقر السيد سونغ.
You forgot?
نسيت؟
I mean, they're close.
أعني، إنهم قريبون.
They wouldn't...
لن يفعلوا...
Get going!
انطلق!
Qiu!
تشيو!
Wrong way.
الطريق الخطأ.
Yes, sir!
نعم، سيدي!
Stop!
توقف!
- If you stop chasing, I'll stop running! - Why are you running in the first place?
- إذا توقفت عن الملاحقة، سأتوقف عن الركض! - لماذا تركض من الأساس؟
- I'll stop running. - I'll stop chasing. Master Song!
- سأتوقف عن الركض. - سأتوقف عن الملاحقة. السيد سونغ!
You... You liar!
أنت... أنت كاذب!
I knew I couldn't trust you!
كنت أعلم أنني لا أستطيع الوثوق بك!
(Last night, Zhao Tai's medication wore off.)
(الليلة الماضية، توقفت مفعول دواء تشاو تاي.)
(Luckily, he woke up to eat something in the middle of the night.)
(لحسن الحظ، استيقظ ليأكل شيئًا في منتصف الليل.)
(I dumped all medicine into his food.)
(وضعت كل الدواء في طعامه.)
Will I stay for dinner? No, thanks.
هل سأبقى لتناول العشاء؟ لا، شكرًا.
(Miss Lichun...)
(السيدة لي تشون...)
(She's holding my hand...)
(هي تمسك بيدي...)
Stop running...
توقف عن الركض...
Stop chasing me...
توقف عن ملاحقتي...
I'll stop...
سأتوقف...
Listen...
اسمع...
If you chase me again, Mr. Ma is going to show up!
إذا لاحقتني مرة أخرى، السيد ما سيظهر!
No way. Mr. Ma went to the magistrate's mansion.
مستحيل. السيد ما ذهب إلى قصر القاضي.
He's not coming.
لن يأتي.
You tricked me, huh?
لقد خدعتني، أليس كذلك؟
Fine.
حسنًا.
Kill me if you must!
اقتلني إذا كان لابد من ذلك!
I can't run anymore...
لا أستطيع الركض بعد الآن...
Kill you?
أقتلك؟
What?
ماذا؟
Mr. Ma told me to come here.
السيد ما أخبرني أن آتي إلى هنا.
He said I should testify
قال إنه يجب أن أشهد
and have you
وأجعلك
write a statement.
تكتب بيانًا.
Right?
صحيح؟
Right.
صحيح.
What?
ماذا؟
Did you not get the message from Qiu?
ألم تحصل على الرسالة من تشيو؟
No one told me anything!
لم يخبرني أحد بأي شيء!
You lunatics!
أنتم مجانين!
Why didn't you say that earlier?
لماذا لم تقل ذلك في وقت سابق؟
This way, please.
من هنا، من فضلك.
Magistrate Zhao.
قاضي الحافظة تشاو.
You asked to see me?
هل طلبت رؤيتي؟
Mr. Ma, you're here.
السيد ما، أنت هنا.
You brat!
أيها الشقي!
Mr. Ma is here! Come clean right now!
السيد ما هنا! اعترف الآن!
Tai!
تاي!
Tai! You've left this world too soon!
تاي! لقد غادرت هذا العالم مبكرًا جدًا!
Don't leave me behind...
لا تتركني خلفك...
Father.
أبي.
I just had something on my mind.
كنت أفكر في شيء ما.
Why are you so distraught?
لماذا أنت مضطرب هكذا؟
You scared the life out of me!
أخفتني بشدة!
Talk.
تحدث.
It happened about two months ago.
حدث ذلك قبل حوالي شهرين.
Jiao.
جياو.
Come on, drink!
هيا، اشرب!
Drink up!
اشرب!
Let's drink together!
لنشرب معًا!
Cheers!
في صحتك!
What's the matter, Mr. Zhao?
ما الأمر، سيد تشاو؟
What else?
ماذا أيضًا؟
It's that Song Yuan!
إنه سونغ يوان!
He's like a mad dog!
إنه مثل الكلب المجنون!
He won't leave Mr. Zhao alone!
لن يترك السيد تشاو وشأنه!
He's relentless.
إنه لا يرحم.
Song Yuan's been running all over town,
كان سونغ يوان يجوب المدينة،
collecting every detail about your past deeds.
يجمع كل التفاصيل عن أفعالك السابقة.
After all that fuss,
بعد كل تلك الضجة،
I can't even enjoy myself when I'm here anymore.
لم أعد أستطيع الاستمتاع بوقتي هنا بعد الآن.
Tong.
تونغ.
Don't be upset. Come on.
لا تنزعج. هيا.
Let's enjoy ourselves.
لنستمتع بوقتنا.
Mr. Zhao, don't worry so much.
سيد تشاو، لا تقلق كثيرًا.
Song Yuan could be
قد يكون سونغ يوان
running all over town, but he won't make it here.
يجوب المدينة، لكنه لن يصل إلى هنا.
Besides,
بالإضافة إلى ذلك،
we have company as precious as gold here.
لدينا هنا رفقة ثمينة مثل الذهب.
Gold?
ذهب؟
What if I manage to get Song Yuan here?
ماذا لو تمكنت من إحضار سونغ يوان هنا؟
That's brilliant! Absolutely brilliant!
هذا رائع! رائع للغاية!
Come on!
هيا!
Let's all raise a toast to Mr. Zhao.
لنرفع جميعًا نخبًا للسيد تشاو.
Here, here!
هنا، هنا!
Cheers!
في صحتك!
Goodness!
يا إلهي!
Who is this handsome young gentleman?
من هذا الشاب الوسيم؟
What do you think? Not bad, right?
ما رأيك؟ ليس سيئًا، أليس كذلك؟
I could barely recognize you.
لم أتمكن بالكاد من التعرف عليك.
Is this the guy?
هل هذا هو الرجل؟
Mr. Zhao had me
السيد تشاو طلب مني
make him a mask from human skin.
أن أصنع له قناعًا من جلد بشري.
The one that was badly burned.
الذي كان محترقًا بشدة.
A human skin mask?
قناع من جلد بشري؟
My craftsmanship is well-known
مهارتي معروفة
far and wide.
في كل مكان.
Once you put that mask on,
بمجرد أن تضع ذلك القناع،
not even your own mother could recognize you.
لن تتمكن حتى والدتك من التعرف عليك.